Privacy and Cookie Policy
=========================

Valid from 7th of May 2020, updated July 13th, 2026.

**1\. Introduction**
--------------------

In this Privacy Policy you will find information about how Dune Analytics AS ("Dune") processes your personal data when you use our website and our Dune Products. At the end of this policy, you will find our Cookie Policy, providing information about Dune's use of cookies.

References to "we" and "us" in the following refers to the company Dune Analytics AS.

Dune is the controller of the processing activities described in this policy.

This Privacy Policy assists you as a user of the Dune Product to understand which Personal Data we collect, why we collect Personal Data, how we use Personal Data and the data privacy rights you have as a user of the Dune Product.

**2\. Purpose and basis for the information we collect**
--------------------------------------------------------

Dune collects personal data for the purposes of providing the Dune Product, website analysis and improvement, direct marketing, and product updates.

**Personal Data** is defined as any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person.

Any processing of Personal Data by Dune is conducted in accordance with applicable data privacy legislation. We process your data for the following purposes:

### **2.1. Providing the Dune Product**

We will collect and process the following Personal Data when you use the Dune Product:

*   Name
*   Username
*   E-mail address
*   IP-address
*   Web browser
*   Navigation information on [dune.com](http://dune.com/) or other domains where the Dune Product is accessible

Personal Data collected for offering the Dune Product are used in the following ways:

*   To administrate and provide you with the Dune Product.
*   To contact you for software updates or changes to this Privacy Policy or other agreements relevant for your use of the Dune Product.

Users should note that the social nature of the Dune Product means that anything you create with the free service will be publicly viewable. See Terms of Service for more information.

**Legal basis:** To fulfill an agreement with you, see article 6(1)(b) of the General Data Protection Regulation.

### **2.2. Website and product analysis and improvement**

We will collect and process the following Personal Data for website and product analysis and improvement:

*   Name
*   E-mail address
*   IP-address
*   Web browser
*   Navigation information on [dune.com](http://dune.com/) or other domains where the Dune Product is accessible

Personal Data collected for website analysis and improvement are used in the following ways:

*   To analyze trends and usage patterns on the website
*   To improve the website by adapting its configuration and design to behavioral patterns

We gather the data through the use of "cookies". Cookies are small files which are stored on your computer by your web browser.

**Legal basis:** We consider that we have a legitimate interest under article 6(1)(f) of the General Data Protection Regulation. Our legitimate interest consists of being able to provide and improve our services.

### **2.3. Troubleshooting or support**

We may process your Personal Data and usage logs when you submit a request for troubleshooting or support for your use of the Dune Product. Such Personal Data and usage logs are not used for any other purposes than to provide you with the requested support or troubleshooting.

We will collect and process the following Personal Data for troubleshooting and support:

*   Name
*   E-mail address
*   IP-address
*   Web browser
*   Navigation information on [dune.com](http://dune.com/) or other domains where the Dune Product is accessible

**Legal basis:** To fulfill an agreement with you, see article 6(1)(b) of the General Data Protection Regulation.

### **2.4. Direct marketing and product updates**

Dune Analytics AS will use your name and contact information in order to keep you updated on any product launches, software updates or similar marketing related communications related to the Dune Product. You may opt out of marketing communications by using the unsubscribe link included in such communications. We collect and use the following information for marketing purposes:

*   Name
*   E-mail address
*   Navigation information on [dune.com](http://dune.com/) or other domains where the Dune Product is accessible

**Legal basis:** We consider that we have a legitimate interest under article 6(1)(f) of the General Data Protection Regulation. Our legitimate interest consists of our business interest in reaching out to users and send relevant information.

### **2.5. Recruitment**

For the purpose of recruitment, we will process your personal data. By applying to a position on our "Careers"-site we will process the data you submit. We will process the following data, depending on what information you submit:

*   Name
*   E-mail
*   Location
*   Social media profile
*   Resume
*   Introduction and why you are applying for the position

The Personal Data will be used to consider whether you are a potential candidate for our positions.

**Legal basis:** To fulfill an agreement with you, see article 6(1)(b) of the General Data Protection Regulation.

### **2.6. AI-Powered Features**

Dune offers AI-powered features, including Dune Agent, natural-language-to-SQL, query assistance, query explanation, and query/chart description or visualization assistance ("Dune AI"). These features process your inputs and relevant product context to generate responses or suggestions.

Dune currently uses Anthropic, PBC, located in the United States, as its large language model provider for Dune AI. Dune sends Anthropic the inputs and context needed to provide the relevant Dune AI feature.

Dune does not retain user prompts submitted to Dune AI, except as required for transient processing, legal compliance, security, or abuse prevention. Dune does not use Dune AI inputs or outputs to train models.

Anthropic states that API inputs and outputs are deleted from its backend systems within 30 days by default, subject to exceptions for legal requirements, usage policy enforcement, or separately agreed retention settings. Anthropic also states that it does not use commercial/API inputs or outputs to train its models by default.

You should not include sensitive personal data, confidential information, or information you are not authorized to submit in Dune AI inputs. Enterprise customers may request that Dune AI features are disabled for their organization where supported by their plan or separate agreement with Dune.

See our [Trust Center](https://trust.dune.com/) for the full list of sub-processors.

### **2.7. Use of AI tools**

We process limited Personal Data (such as your name, username, and account/usage metadata), using approved third-party AI tools to operate, debug, troubleshoot, and analyse usage of the Dune Product. We only use AI providers operating under no-training and zero-retention terms (inputs are not used to train their models and are not retained). We do not process your private query content, uploaded data, or payment data in these tools. The AI providers we use are listed as sub-processors on our Trust Center. _Legal basis: legitimate interest, art. 6(1)(f)._

**3\. Retention period**
------------------------

We retain Personal Data only for as long as necessary for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy, unless a longer retention period is required to comply with legal or regulatory obligations, resolve disputes, maintain security logs, or enforce our agreements. Account data is deleted or anonymized following a deletion request, subject to any legally required retention. Support records, billing records, security logs, and backups may be retained for limited additional periods in accordance with Dune’s internal retention and data management policies.

**4\. Who we share your information with**
------------------------------------------

Dune Analytics will not share the Personal Data of its users with any third parties, except when we have legal grounds for sharing the data or it is required under any statutory obligations of which Dune Analytics AS is subject to.

We share your data with our processors (sub-processors), with the sole purpose of providing and operating the service. We share Personal Data with sub-processors solely to provide and operate the service. Our current list of sub-processors, with purpose and location, is maintained on our Trust Center at [trust.dune.com](http://trust.dune.com/).

For all sub-processors located outside the EEA, we rely on appropriate transfer mechanisms, including EU Standard Contractual Clauses, to ensure that transfers are made in accordance with applicable data protection legislation.

**5\. Security measures**
-------------------------

Dune implements appropriate technical and organizational measures to protect Personal Data against unauthorized access, alteration, disclosure, or destruction. These measures include encryption of data in transit and at rest, multi-factor authentication for access to systems containing Personal Data, role-based access controls, and regular security testing. For more information, see our Trust Center.

**6\. Data breach notification**
--------------------------------

In the event of a personal data breach that is likely to result in a risk to your rights and freedoms, Dune will notify the relevant supervisory authority without undue delay and, where feasible, within 72 hours. Where the breach is likely to result in a high risk to your rights and freedoms, Dune will also notify affected individuals without undue delay.

**7\. Your rights**
-------------------

When providing us with your Personal Data, you may request access to your Personal Data, as well as information on how we process your Personal Data. You may also request rectification, erasure and restriction of the processing, as well as to have your Personal Data exported in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format (data portability).

Requests pursuant to the above rights may submitted to: **support@dune.com**

You may also file a complaint to your applicable data protection authority if you are of the opinion that Dune Analytics has failed to comply with your rights as a data subject.

**8\. International data transfers**
------------------------------------

Dune is situated in Norway within the European Economic Area (EEA). Some of our sub-processors are located outside the EEA, including in the United States. For all transfers of Personal Data outside the EEA, we ensure that appropriate safeguards are in place, including EU Standard Contractual Clauses, in accordance with Chapter V of the GDPR.

**9\. Changes to this Privacy policy**
--------------------------------------

Dune may update this Privacy Policy from time to time. When we do this, we will post the updated Privacy Policy on this page, add the date of the last update at the top of this page, and record the change in our Trust Center at [https://trust.dune.com](https://trust.dune.com/). You understand and agree that your continued use of any Dune Product after we have made any such changes constitutes your acceptance of the updated Privacy Policy.

**10\. Cookie Policy**
----------------------

Cookies are text files containing small amounts of information which are downloaded to your computer or mobile device when you visit Dune's website and allow us to recognize your device.

According to applicable legal regulations for electronic communications, cookies may be stored or accessed on your equipment only based on your consent, except for cookies that are strictly necessary in order to provide the services on Dune's website. Dune uses both cookies that are strictly necessary to provide our services (**Necessary Cookies**) as well as cookies that provide us analytics about the performance of our website, enable webflow and Search Engine Optimization and support marketing (**Non-necessary Cookies**).

You can decide whether to accept Non-necessary Cookies through our cookie banner or cookie settings tool and may change or withdraw your choice at any time. You may also restrict cookies through your web browser settings. If you do not agree with Necessary Cookies being used, you should leave the website and stop using our services.

### **Necessary Cookies**

*   **Security (attack prevention)** — These cookies allow us to provide cloud cybersecurity and DDoS (attack) mitigation. These include Cloudflare cookies and CSRF.
*   **Authenticated session liveness** (for authenticated users) — These cookies allow us to authenticate our users and keep them logged into their accounts. These include auth-refresh and auth-user.
*   **Stripe** — These cookies are used to support payment processing functionality. They help detect fraud and ensure secure transactions.

### **Non-necessary Cookies**

*   **Cloudflare** — Provides cloud cybersecurity and DDoS mitigation services. Cloudflare uses programming code to collect information about your interaction with our websites. The cookie contains information related to the calculation of Cloudflare's proprietary bot score and, when anomaly detection is enabled on bot management, a session identifier. The information in the cookie (other than time-related information) is encrypted and can only be decrypted by Cloudflare. This code is only active while you are on our websites and expires after 30 minutes of continuous inactivity by the end user.
*   **Amplitude** — Provides analytics to enhance the experience of our visitors to our website and to better understand how the website is used. The storage period for Amplitude Cookies is 1 year.
*   **Google Analytics** — Used to measure and evaluate how users interact with website content across browsing sessions.
*   **HubSpot Tracker** — Helps us track visitors to Dune's website. Every time a visitor lands on our website, HubSpot will check for an existing tracking cookie. If one does not exist, a cookie will be associated with that visitor and will log every page that person visits moving forward.
*   **Google Search Console** — Helps us monitor, maintain, and troubleshoot our website's presence in Google Search results.
*   **PostHog** — Provides product analytics to understand how users interact with website features. Note: this may be injected by a third-party integration rather than set directly by Dune.
*   **Google Ads (Conversion Linker)** — Used to measure the effectiveness of advertising campaigns by tracking conversions from Google Ads. The \_gcl\_au cookie links ad clicks to on-site actions.
